# **DUSTIN HARRELL**

Alexandria, VA 22310 | 804-691-7212 | dhharr@gmail.com

## **SUMMARY**

I am a customer-centered technology analytics professional with more than a decade of experience across multiple industries. My work includes gathering, developing, and analyzing business requirements in order to develop and implement complex solutions that increase customer efficiencies, manage change, reduce risk, and improve performance. My focus on customer relationship management, business intelligence, and cloud computing technologies in the workplace have delivered valuable outcomes for customers, with sponsorship from C-suite leaders. I have advanced language skills in Spanish and Mandarin Chinese. I have a history of excelling in team oriented and diverse environments through exceptional communication, analytical, technical, and creative skills.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DELOITTE CONSULTING - Arlington, Virginia - May 2013 - September 2019

### **Business Technology Consultant/Systems Engineer**

- Practitioner in the Deloitte Digital offering portfolio group that combines leading digital and creative capabilities to deliver innovative customer and marketing solutions by a unique agency/consultancy model. Applied solutions to clients across public services, financial services, insurance, health care, transportation, and education sectors.
- Facilitate solution design and delivery on platforms such as Salesforce.com, Azure, and custom enterprise Java Applications using Project Management Body of Knowledge (PMBOK) methods and Agile best practices.
- Configured applications using automation tools and object oriented programming. Built data
  migration and web services integration solutions using Extract, Transform, and Load (ETL) and
  middleware tools such as Informatica and Mulesoft. Maintained software development
  collaboration with teammates using tools such as JIRA, IBM Rational, and Visual Studio Team
  Services.
- Served as Scrum Master for enterprise application rationalization projects and led design and quality initiatives for API integration architecture concepts.
- Led configuration efforts in the construction of a rules engine for a convolutional neural network, machine learning based text analytics capability to bring faster analysis to unstructured data sets.

LOGIXML – McLean, Virginia – September 2012 – February 2013

### **Business Development Representative**

- Proactively identified new sales and product opportunities by gathering customer requirements and guided prospects through qualification process to assess business and technical fit of LogiXML's Business Intelligence and Application Development Platform to customer use case.
- Worked closely with marketing operations and communications, product management, and sales
  engineering teams to develop and implement strategic programs to build awareness and growth
  prospects for LogiXML.

EVERLEARN GROUP - Shanghai, China - August 2010 - May 2012

# **DUSTIN HARRELL**

Alexandria, VA 22310 | 804-691-7212 | dhharr@gmail.com

## **Program Analyst for FasTrack English Program**

- Led interactive classes and demos to over 350 young participants and strengthened my communication and presentation skills in a broad context by delivering interactive presentations in a multilingual environment.
- Led process improvement team to better understand and improve the classroom experience from a student perspective. Developed and monitored key student performance indicators.
- Assessed the need of classroom projects, gathered functional and other application requirements, and facilitated program software development projects with engineering teams by leveraging HTML, JavaScript, and RDBMS technologies.

WEATHER CRAFTERS HEATING AND AIR CONDITIONING - Chester, VA - July 2009-July 2010

## **Project Coordinator**

- Built financial sales and cost/benefit analysis models for sales consultants and service technicians.
   Gathered requirements in the installation of over 30 new/retrofit HVAC systems. Advanced user of the Microsoft Office Suite (to include Visio and MS Project) and Siebel CRM.
- Discovered, analyzed, interpreted, and presented data findings to different departments of the
  organization in order to improve organizational decision making and customer service. Maintained
  and improved databases related to customer relationship management, inventory management,
  and project management.
- Ensured compliance with Section 608 of the Clean Air Act of 1990 with respect to refrigerant recycling. Completed NATE Core Service Examination. Obtained Certified Green Professional Designation from the National Association of Homebuilders.

#### **EDUCATION**

**COLLEGE OF WILLIAM AND MARY** --- Williamsburg, Virginia – Graduated 2009 Bachelor of Business Administration with an International Emphasis: Major in Finance, Concentration in Marketing, and Minor in Psychology.

#### OTHER SKILLS, CERTIFICATIONS, AND ACTIVITIES

- Certified Salesforce.com Developer, Administrator, and Service Cloud Consultant.
- Certified Scaled Agile Framework Practitioner (SAFe).
- Certified Customer Experience Management Professional (Medallia Software).
- Certified Six Sigma Yellow Belt.
- Adobe Experience Manager Front End Development Certificate.
- VMware Virtual SAN Fundamentals.
- Accredited Amazon Web Services (AWS) Business and Technical Professional.

#### LinkedIn Profile